[Road to Success]
[찬여번성: 별처럼 빛나리]
[Episode 30]
[제30화]
Later,
이따
use this nail to pin the eel down.
못으로 드렁허리를 박으면
I'll handle the rest.
나머지는 내가 할게
This is...
이게
your...
아저씨가
s-signature dish?
제일 잘하는 요리군요
Yeah,
그래
braised eel.
드렁허리 조림
Let me tell you,
있잖아
my wife and Wang Tian both love it.
왕톈 엄마랑 왕톈이 이걸 좋아하거든
W-Wang Tian loves eel?
왕톈이 이걸 좋아해요?
You're not afraid of eels, are you?
설마 드렁허리도 무서워하는 건 아니지?
I'm telling you,
내가 말해 주는데
Wang Tian hates cowardly men the most.
왕톈은 겁 많은 남자를 제일 싫어해
I-I'm not!
아니에요
I never said I was afraid.
무섭다고 한 적 없어요
I can do it.
할 수 있어요
Hold it.
잡아
Remember, nail the head.
머리에 박는 거 잊지 마
Be careful not to nail your hand.
손 조심하고
Auntie!
아주머니
You're back!
오셨어요?
Yu Bo, you came.
위보 왔어?
Why are you covered in so much mud?
근데 왜 이렇게 흙투성이에요?
My mom insisted on checking out the construction site.
엄마가 기어코 공사장에 가자고 해서
You're a civil engineering professor,
엄마는 토목과 교수님이지
not a contractor.
현장 소장도 아닌데
Look at the mess on your clothes.
꼴이 이게 뭐예요?
A student of mine wanted me to take a look at their project.
제자가 프로젝트를 봐 달라고 하는데
Of course, I had to go, right?
당연히 가 봐야지
Yeah.
그렇죠
Wang Tian, let me tell you...
왕톈, 있잖아
Well...
그...
What's wrong?
왜 그래?
Why are you gagging?
뭐야?
Am I making you sick?
날 보자마자 토하는 거야?
No, I...
그게...
It's just a reflex.
본능적인 반응이야
A reflex?
본능적인 반응?
Excuse me.
잠깐만
You guys clean up first.
일단 계세요
I n-need to go to the bathroom.
화장실 좀 다녀올게요
Is he okay?
괜찮은 건가?
Mom,
엄마
are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
-Hello, Professor Kang. -And this is?
- 캉 선생님, 안녕하세요 - 이분은 누구야?
This is Ms. Lin Wanxing,
이분은 린완싱 선생님이에요
a fellow teacher
어머니처럼 학생들을 가르치고
and my girlfriend.
제 여자 친구예요
Hello, Ms. Lin.
린 선생님, 반가워요
Nice to meet you.
안녕하세요
Kang Qiao.
캉차오
You're back.
왔어?
W-What happened?
이게 다 뭐야?
Nothing. I'm just happy to be home.
별거 아니야 집에 오니까 좋네
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
I-I'll go wash up.
좀 씻고 올게요
I'm a mess.
꼴이 말이 아니네
You guys keep her company.
두 사람이 손님 좀 챙겨
You invited Ms. Lin over
린 선생님을 불렀으면서
without telling Mom beforehand?
엄마한테 미리 말도 안 해요?
And Ms. Lin just happened to catch Mom looking so disheveled.
하필 엄마가 제일 창피할 때 만났잖아요
Wang,
라오왕
you're dead.
아빠는 망했어요
Wait.
아니...
I made eel.
드렁허리...
And braised!
조림도 했는데?
Let's all raise a glass to welcome
다 같이 잔 들고
Ms. Lin Wanxing.
린 선생님을 환영합시다
Thank you.
감사합니다
Welcome, welcome.
환영해요
Oh, right.
참
This is your favorite,
이거 당신이 제일 좋아하는
braised eel.
드렁허리 조림이야
If you don't like it,
안 좋아하면
let's switch to another dish.
다른 거 먹어
Let's switch to another dish.
이건
This is the one you love.
당신이 좋아하는 거잖아
Thank you.
고마워
This one...
이건...
Let me do it. Let me.
내가 줄게
How about this?
아니면
Well,
내일
tomorrow I'll come back and make you
내가 돌아와서
braised soft-shell turtle—
자라 조림을 해 줄게
freshly slaughtered.
바로 잡아서
Yu.
위보가
Yu can do it.
아주 잘해
He has great knife skills.
칼질을 아주 잘하더라고
No, no, r-really, I can't.
아니에요
My knife skills aren't good.
저 칼질 잘 못 해요
Not good at all.
진짜예요
This is Wanxing's first time visiting our home.
린 선생님이 집에 처음 오는 건데
Why didn't you tell me beforehand?
왜 나한테 말도 안 했어?
Why keep it from me?
나한테만 비밀이야?
Well...
그게...
It's just that
당신이 요즘
you've been so busy lately with research,
연구 때문에 바쁘잖아
writing papers,
논문도 써야 하고
and running around to construction sites.
공사 현장도 가야 하고
I didn't want you to wear yourself out.
당신이 힘들까 봐
So,
그래서
whatever I could handle myself,
내가 할 수 있는 일은
I just went ahead a-and did it.
알아서 하려고 한 거지
This whole table of dishes—
한 상 가득 차린 걸 보니
it must have taken you all afternoon.
오후 내내 준비했겠네
Just about 4 or 5 hours.
네댓 시간밖에 안 걸렸어
It was fine.
별거 아니야
Mom,
엄마
for all the hard work Dad put into this meal,
아빠가 요리하느라 고생한 걸 봐서
forgive him this time.
이번 한 번만 봐줘요
Dad,
아빠
punish yourself with a drink,
벌주 한 잔 드시면
and this matter will be over.
없던 일이 될 거예요
That's my boy.
내 친아들 맞아?
Your Majesty,
우리 부인
I was wrong.
잘못했어요
Blessings to the Empress Dowager.
만수무강하세요, 태후마마
At ease.
예를 거두게
Wanxing,
완싱
try this dish.
이거 한번 먹어 봐요
It's my husband's specialty.
이 사람이 잘하는 요리예요
Give it a try.
한번 먹어 봐요
This is my signature dish, braised eel.
내 특기인 드렁허리 조림이야
It's a secret recipe.
내 비법으로 만드는 거라
You can't get it anywhere else.
밖에서는 못 먹어
Come on, try it.
한번 먹어 봐
My wife and Tian both love it the most.
우리 집사람이랑 딸이 제일 좋아하는 거야
Ms. Lin, I want some.
린 선생님, 나도 먹고 싶어요
You just can't help yourself, can you?
넌 또 왜 끼어들어?
These noodles look great.
국수가 맛있어 보이네요
Let me try the broth first.
국물 맛부터 볼게요
The broth is what makes the noodles, right?
국수는 국물이 중요하잖아요
This is also Chairman Wang's specialty.
이것도 아빠가 잘하는 요리야
Dad,
아빠
the broth is made from eel bones, right?
이 국물은 드렁허리 뼈로 우려낸 거죠?
Right.
맞아
You just love the flavor, right?
네가 이걸 좋아하잖아
Uncle and Auntie,
저기... 아저씨, 아주머니
let me propose a toast.
제가 한 잔 올리고...
I need to use the restroom.
화장실 좀 다녀올게요
What a lightweight.
주량이 저게 뭐야?
Wanxing,
린 선생
a toast to you.
같이 한잔하자고
What are you doing?
뭐 하는 거야?
Making her drink on her first visit?
처음 온 사람한테 술을 권하면 어떡해?
I'll finish mine, and you do as you like.
난 다 마실 테니까 린 선생은 편하게 마셔
-Okay? -You're putting her on the spot.
마시라는 거야, 말라는 거야?
If she doesn't drink, it's disrespectful to you, right?
안 마시면 당신을 무시하는 거지?
That's not it.
아니야
In this house,
우리 집에선
whether you respect me or not doesn't matter.
난 신경 쓸 거 없고
But you must respect the lady of the house,
안주인만 존중하면 돼
right?
그렇지?
Blessings to the Empress Dowager.
만수무강하세요, 태후마마
Come on, come on.
자
Right,
참
Wanxing,
린 선생
do you know
왜 내가 린 선생을 처음 봤는데도
why I felt an instant connection with you?
친근하게 느끼는지 알아?
That's because
왜냐하면
you're very much like our Professor Kang.
린 선생은 우리 집사람이랑 정말 닮았어
I didn't study hard when I was a kid,
난 어릴 때 공부를 안 해서
so I'm not very educated.
무식해
One year, when I was doing business in Shenzhen,
내가 선전에서 사업할 때
I had a client whose surname was Situ.
만난 사장님 성이 '쓰투'였는데
I even
내가
tried to act clever and asked him,
잘난 척하면서 그분께 물어봤어
"Sir,
선생님
is it that your father's surname is Si
혹시 아버님 성이 '쓰'고
and your mother's surname is Tu?"
어머님 성이 '투'인가요?
That was so embarrassing.
정말 창피했지
Things like that happened a lot.
이런 일이 한두 번이 아니야
So
그래서
I've always believed
나는 늘
that every family
집안에
needs an intelligent, well-educated woman—
교양 있는 여자가 있어야
that's what makes a household prosper.
집안이 흥한다고 생각해
Remember that.
알았지?
Back then, I basically wore Professor Kang down with my persistence
내가 끈질기게 매달려서
until she agreed to be with me.
겨우 우리 집사람을 잡았어
I heard you were once the top scorer on the college entrance exam, right?
대학 입시 수석이라고 들었는데
What was your score?
몇 점이었어?
Seven hundred and six points.
706점이요
See? See?
이것 봐라
Compared to our Professor Kang,
우리 집사람이랑 비교해도
you're no couch.
전혀 뒤지지 않잖아
"No slouch."
막상막하네
Right, it's "no slouch." No slouch.
막상... 막하
Anyway,
아무튼
thank you so much
정말 고마워
for choosing our Wang Fa.
우리 왕파를 좋게 봐 줘서
To be honest, I also think
솔직히 나도
you two are a perfect match.
왕파랑 린 선생이 정말 잘 어울린다고 생각해
He's not like
저 밖에 있는
those delusional guys out there who are
두꺼비같이
always chasing someone way out of their league.
백조를 넘보지도 않고
Right, daughter?
그렇지, 딸?
Dad.
아빠
Come on, eat up.
다들 먹자
Let's have a drink together.
다 같이 한잔해요
Come on, come on.
그래
Cheers, cheers.
한잔하자
Cheers.
자
Welcome, Wanxing.
환영해요, 린 선생님
Welcome, welcome.
환영해
Don't drink too much.
조금만 마셔
I'm just happy.
기분이 좋아서
Just a little bit.
조금
Just a little.
마시는 거야
Then eat more.
그럼 많이 먹어
That's amazing.
정말 대단하네요
Don't let me have all the fun.
나만 놀면 안 되지
You young people,
젊은이들이
be more lively.
분위기 좀 띄워
Don't just sit there with your phones.
휴대폰 그만 보고
Come here. Come on.
다들 이리 와
-Okay, I'll play. -Go.
- 그래 - 빨리 와
Let me play with you.
제가 할게요
Why do you have to be part of everything?
넌 왜 여기저기 다 끼어들어?
I'm actually pretty good at this.
저 다트 잘해요
Really.
진짜예요
Is that so?
그래?
I may be getting on in years,
내가 나이는 좀 있어도
but I still have a strong competitive streak.
승부욕은 강한 편이야
See? I knew you were no good.
넌 안 된다고 했잖아
And you just had to...
진짜...
Wanxing,
완싱
Wang Fa, come here.
왕파, 이리 와
Wanxing, if you don't know how,
완싱은 못 하면
let Wang Fa teach you.
왕파한테 배워
Come on, come on.
이리 와
She has zero athletic talent.
완싱은 운동 신경이 없어요
I'll do it.
제가 할게요
Let me play some rounds with our chairman.
제가 회장님과 함께하겠습니다
Let Wanxing play.
완싱한테 하라고 하라니까
-Dad is on a completely different level. -Let me get familiar with it first.
- 아빠 다트 잘하잖아요 - 적응할 시간은 주세요
He used to spear fish on the production team back in the day.
저 사람 생산팀에서 작살로 물고기 잡았대
Come here and let the kids play.
애들한테 양보하고 이리 와
Well, some things are better left unsaid.
알아도 모르는 척 좀 해
Let me give it a try.
내가 한번 해 볼게요
How about
우리
we have a round?
내기할까요?
Sure.
좋아요
Okay.
난
I think that's fine.
할 수 있어요
He sucks at darts.
얘 다트 엄청 못 해요
Anyway, if you lose,
너 지면
you have to do whatever she says.
린 선생님이 시키는 걸 해야 해
I'll give you a head start.
한 판을 봐줄 테니까
You go first.
당신이 먼저 해요
This is going to be good.
재밌겠네요
Challenge accepted.
도전을 받아들이죠
-Clearly didn't inherit my genes. -You really suck,
- 내 유전자는 못 받았네 - 너무 못한다
little brother.
동생
Step aside.
비켜 봐요
Come on, Wanxing!
린 선생님, 파이팅
Not bad.
잘하네요
See? I knew Wanxing was good.
린 선생님이 잘할 줄 알았어요
Okay, you lost.
왕파, 네가 졌어
What do you want him to do?
뭘 시킬래요?
I have a suggestion.
제안이 하나 있는데
Have you seen the photos of him in women's clothes?
왕파 여장한 사진 본 적 있어요?
The one
그러니까
where he's wearing a qipao with a flower crown?
치파오 입고 머리 장식 한 거요
I just saw the photo upstairs.
위층에서 봤어요
Isn't that hilarious?
진짜 웃기지 않아요?
Okay.
됐다
How about a qipao and flower crown?
치파오 입고 머리 장식 하는 거 어때?
Are you asking for it?
죽고 싶냐?
I think that's a great idea.
괜찮은 제안 같아요
Duly noted.
기억해 둘게요
That's so fun, honey.
좋네, 여보
Come on, come on,
이리 와
honey,
여보
how about I take you along to try the flower crown too?
나도 당신이랑 같이 머리 장식 하러 갈까?
Come on, we're already here.
기왕 하는 김에
Just play one round.
한 판만 하자니까
No.
싫어
I'm very busy.
바빠
We have a guest,
손님도 왔는데
and you're just sitting here glued to your phone.
휴대폰만 보고 있어?
Fine.
알았어
If I win,
내가 이기면
you're not allowed to hang around my office for no reason anymore.
앞으로 내 사무실에 함부로 얼쩡거리지 마
And if I win,
그럼 내가 이기면
you have to agree to one request of mine.
내 부탁 들어줘
Deal.
알았어
Give the darts to them.
두 사람 놀게 둬요
You got this.
파이팅
Yu Bo used to compete in
위보는 영국에서
professional dart tournaments back in the UK.
프로 다트 대회에 나갔었어요
No wonder he's so confident.
어쩐지 자신만만하더라고요
Nice!
좋아
As expected of Kang Qiao's daughter.
역시 캉차오의 딸이야
So amazing.
대단해
Wait.
아니...
Seriously?
이게 뭐예요?
When Wanxing hit the board,
아까 린 선생님이 맞혔을 때는
you applauded so enthusiastically.
박수 소리가 엄청 뜨거웠는데
How come it's so cold when it's my turn?
왜 제 차례가 되니까 이렇게 차가워지는 거죠?
Alright, go ahead.
됐으니까
What's your request?
뭘 원하는지 말해 봐
My request is that...
내가 원하는 건...
you really look at me.
누나가 나를 제대로 봐 주는 거야
Look me in the eye, properly.
나라는 사람을 제대로 봐 줘
I just did.
봤어
You're even more ordinary than this quarter's financial report.
우리 회사 이번 분기 보고서보다 평범하네
My sister's a master roaster.
우리 누나 진짜 말 한번 독하게 한다
How am I a master roaster?
내가 뭘 어쨌다고?
Your words are savage,
말만 독한 게 아니라
and your actions are even worse.
행동도 못됐어
-Let's all play. Let me show you. -You started that flower crown thing.
- 내가 시범을 보여 줄게 - 비녀도 누나가 꽂았잖아
I still haven't settled that score with you.
나 아직 그 일 마음에 담아 두고 있거든
You were smiling so happily in that photo
너 어릴 때 사진 좀 봐
from when you were a kid.
얼마나 해맑게 웃고 있어?
I'll stick this dart in you.
다트로 쏴 버린다
D-Don't...
하지 마
Dad,
아빠
look at him.
쟤 좀 봐요
Let Dad show you how it's done.
아빠가 시범 보여 줄게
You can't lose to someone like him.
이런 놈한테 질 수 없지
Watch carefully.
잘 봐
It's too rowdy in here.
여긴 너무 시끄럽죠?
Want to go out for some fresh air?
우리 나가서 바람 좀 쐬요
Standard posture.
자세가 정석이네요
Watch carefully.
잘 봐
-Dad, you're so good. -Well, the old fox still has his tricks.
- 역시 우리 아빠야 - 늙은 생강이 매운 법이야
Please excuse
꼴이 우습죠?
our family.
우리 집안이 좀 그래요
My husband can be a bit much sometimes,
왕파 아빠가 가끔 애 같아서
like a big kid.
사람을 귀찮게 할 때가 있어요
No.
아니에요
He's very nice.
아저씨는 좋은 분이세요
You're all wonderful.
두 분 다 좋으세요
I think you're wonderful too.
린 선생님도 좋은 사람 같아요
The moment I saw you today, I thought,
오늘 처음 봤을 때부터 왜 진작 못 만났을까
"I wish we'd met sooner."
그런 생각이 들었어요
Have you...
혹시
heard about my past?
제 지난 일에 대해 들으셨어요?
Does that matter?
그게 중요한가요?
I like looking at the stars.
나도 별 보는 걸 좋아해요
Take the Andromeda Galaxy
지금 우리가 보고 있는
we're looking at now, for example.
안드로메다자리만 봐도 그래요
It's about
우리한테서
2.54 million light-years away.
254만 광년이나 떨어져 있어요
It's about twice the size of the Milky Way,
은하수보다 두 배 정도 크고
with over a trillion stars.
1조 개가 넘는 항성을 가지고 있어요
Yet to us,
하지만 사람들 눈에는
it's nothing more
그저
than a blurry patch of light.
흐릿한 빛의 점일 뿐이죠
Its vastness,
거대하고
its profundity,
아득하고
its brilliance,
찬란하지만
its true form—
저 별의 진짜 모습은
most people
사실
never truly
대부분의 사람은
understand any of it.
잘 알지 못해요
But so what?
그렇다고 뭐가 달라지나요?
Humanity's limited perspective and incomplete understanding
인간의 단편적인 시각과 한정된 관찰이
don't change
별이라는 존재와
its objective existence
영원한 아름다움에
or its timeless beauty.
영향을 주진 않잖아요
I understand now.
이해해요
Actually, since my husband
사실 남편이
likes you so much,
린 선생님을 이렇게 좋아하는 걸 보면
he must have looked into your past.
뒷조사를 해서일 거예요
He's not as clueless as he seems.
보이는 것처럼 어수룩한 사람은 아니거든요
Of course, he's not exactly smart either.
물론 그렇게 똑똑하지도 않지만요
He went bankrupt twice.
파산도 두 번이나 했어요
Good thing my income is stable.
내 수입이 안정적이라 다행이었지
Otherwise, our whole family would be out on the street.
아니었으면 우리 가족이 다 길바닥에 나앉았을 거예요
Actually...
사실
ever since
왕파는
Wang Fa's student
자기 제자한테
had that accident,
안 좋은 일이 생긴 후로
he's been carrying it with him.
계속 주눅이 들어 있었어요
We tried everything we could
온 가족이 별의별 방법을 다 써서
to make him
왕파를
happy again.
웃게 하려고 했죠
But nothing really worked.
근데 다 어려웠어요
Today,
근데 오늘
seeing him laugh...
왕파가
laugh that wholeheartedly...
저렇게 환하게 웃는 걸 보니
made me so, so happy.
정말 너무 기뻤어요
I think
아마
you're the one who brought him out of it.
린 선생님이 그 애를 밖으로 이끌어준 것 같아요
For your sake, he's
그 애가 린 선생님한테
finally opened his heart again.
마음을 열었어요
Thank you.
고마워요
Son.
아들
Do you have to go back to Hongjing?
꼭 훙징으로 가야겠어?
The guest rooms are all empty.
집에 빈방도 많은데
I can stay!
제가 자고 갈게요
Which room will I be staying in?
어디서 잘까요?
Are you...
혹시...
I'm talking to my son.
아들이랑 얘기 중이잖아
Why are you moving around so much?
네가 왜 난리야?
No,
아니요
Uncle, listen to me!
아저씨, 제 말 좀 들어 보세요
I'm only 3 months and 4 days older than Wang Tian.
제가 왕톈보다 3개월 4일 먼저 태어났어요
Tian, tell him
왕톈, 맞지?
I'm only that much older than you.
내가 먼저 태어났잖아
Okay. Yes, yes.
그래, 맞아
Quick, have the driver take this drunk home.
빨리 택시 불러서 이 주정뱅이 좀 보내
No! I...
싫어
I want Fa to take me back.
왕파가 데려다줬으면 좋겠어
-Okay, I'll take you. -What a lightweight.
- 그래, 데려다줄게 - 주량이 약하네
You're my former manager after all.
내 전 매니저였으니까
Uncle, Auntie, thank you for today.
아저씨, 아주머니 오늘 폐를 끼쳤습니다
Come by often from now on.
앞으로 자주 와요
Come by often.
자주 와
We're really glad you came.
자주 오면 좋지
We're leaving.
갈게요
Drive safely on the road.
조심히 가라
We will.
조심히 갈게요
Such a lightweight.
주량이 저래서...
So weak.
진짜 못 마셔요
What are you smiling about?
왜 웃어요?
I just think
그냥
your family is really lovable.
가족분들이 다 너무 사랑스러워서요
I'm so jealous.
정말 부러워요
From now on...
앞으로
they'll be your family too.
다 당신 가족이에요
Is this how you treat your comrade-in-arms?
전우한테 너무하시네요
Who said I'm his comrade-in-arms?
전우라니요
Then,
그럼
what are we going to do with him tonight?
위보는 오늘 밤에 어떡해요?
Let him stay at your place?
당신 집에서 재워요?
Okay.
그래야죠
That obedient?
말을 잘 듣네요
My family tradition:
우리 집 전통이
the lady of the house makes the decisions.
안주인 말을 듣는 거거든요
♪ Night slips through my fingers ♪
♪ 밤은 손가락 틈새로 흘러 ♪
♪ Embracing the coldness of wakefulness ♪
♪ 깨어 있는 차가움을 감싸고 ♪
♪ Whispering my thoughts alone ♪
♪ 홀로 마음을 속삭이며 ♪
Just kiss her if you want to.
뽀뽀하고 싶으면 하는 거지
Why are you dragging it out?
뭘 꾸물거려?
Let's go home.
집에 가요
Go home.
집에 가자
Do you know
방금 얘가
he was trying to sneak a kiss from you just now?
몰래 뽀뽀하려던 거 알아요?
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
Tell me honestly.
솔직하게 말해 줘요
Am I really that ordinary?
저 되게 평범하죠?
Not at all.
아니요
I think you're very special.
내 눈엔 특별해 보이는데요
Right? Aren't I?
맞죠, 그렇죠?
Aren't I?
그렇다니까요
Let me tell you,
있잖아요
my handsomeness has layers.
내 잘생김은 차원이 다른 잘생김이에요
But Tian just can't appreciate it.
근데 왕톈은 그걸 몰라봐요
I'm warning you,
경고하는데
if you can't keep your hands to yourself,
한 번만 더 망나니처럼 굴면
I'll dump you by the roadside to feed the dogs.
길바닥에 버려서 개 밥으로 만들어 줄 거야
Doggie.
멍멍
Where's the doggie?
멍멍이 어딨어?
The doggie's over there.
멍멍이가 저기 있네
You were trying to sneak a kiss from me just now?
아까 몰래 뽀뽀하려고 했어요?
If I were a doggie,
내가 만약 강아지라면
I'd want to be a Cavalier King Charles Spaniel.
킹 찰스가 될 거야
You'd better not be a dog.
개가 아닌 게 나을걸
Cavalier King Charles Spaniels are so cute.
킹 찰스가 얼마나 귀여운데
Wrong way.
거기 아니야
Rest early. Good night.
푹 쉬어요, 잘 자요
Good night.
잘 자요
Thank you for today.
고생했어요
Thank you for everything today too.
린 선생님도 고생했어요
I could also be a Golden Retriever.
골든 리트리버도 괜찮지
[Wang Fa]
[왕파]
Hello?
여보세요
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
Wang Fa lost to you!
왕파가 선생님한테 졌는데
When are you making him wear a flower crown?
언제 머리 장식 할 거예요?
Can you just sleep quietly, you drunkard?
이 주정뱅이야 조용히 잠이나 자
Hello.
여보세요
Don't listen to him.
신경 쓰지 말아요
Okay.
좋아요
Noted.
기억할게요
Okay...
뭐가
Okay to what?
좋다는 거예요?
To take you to try on a flower crown tomorrow.
내일 머리 장식 체험하러 가요
A bet's a bet, Mr. Win.
내기에 졌으면 벌칙을 받아야죠
Fine.
알았어요
Rest early.
당신도 일찍 쉬어요
You too.
당신도요
Ivory,
샤오바이
a bet's a bet.
내기에 졌으면 벌칙을 받아야지
What do you think of me in this outfit?
이걸 입으라고?
Fix your hair.
머리 좀 만지면 괜찮을까요?
-It looks good. -It really suits you.
- 예쁘다 - 잘 어울려요
Excuse me.
잠시만요
Come, stand a little further forward.
앞으로 서세요
Look here.
이쪽을 보세요
Sorry.
죄송합니다
I think I'm a bit too rough-looking
난 머리에 저런 걸 쓰기엔
and too tan for the flower crown look.
너무 우락부락하고 까만 것 같아요
Relax.
걱정하지 말아요
Places like this usually do pretty heavy makeup.
이런 데서는 다들 화장도 진하게 해
They'll make you nice and fair.
엄청 하얗게 돼요
Let's go.
가요
Okay, one more.
한 장 더 찍을게요
Look.
이것 봐요
[No More Anxiety]
[걱정은 금물]
Do you like this look?
이거 마음에 들어?
So pretty.
진짜 예뻐요
So beautiful.
예쁘다
Here, and there's more in the back too.
뒤에 더 있어요
I like this one as well.
이것도 괜찮은 것 같아요
Yeah.
그렇네요
We should take photos in a few more outfits.
몇 세트 더 찍어요
Okay. Do you have sample pictures?
혹시 샘플 사진 있나요?
Could you recommend a few?
추천 좀 해주세요
Yes, yes.
네
This one's lovely.
예쁘다
Come on.
써 봐요
Does this look good on me?
예뻐요?
Yes.
예뻐요
Let me take a picture of you.
내가 사진 찍어 줄게요
[No More Anxiety]
[걱정은 금물]
Alright.
난 됐어요
Okay.
찍었어요
Your turn.
당신 차례예요
Hey, you two,
잘생기고 예쁜 손님
would you like flower crowns?
머리 장식 할래요?
Ma'am, my boyfriend wants it.
남자 친구가 머리 장식을 하고 싶대요
Sure.
좋아요
My hair's too short to pin anything into, right?
머리가 이렇게 짧은데 할 수 있을까요?
Even bald people can wear flower crowns.
머리가 없어도 할 수 있어요
Hear that?
들었죠?
Even bald people can wear them.
머리가 없어도 할 수 있대요
A bet is a bet.
내기에 졌으면 해야죠
I'll go pick a color for you.
내가 색깔을 골라 줄게요
Yellow, maybe.
노란색이요
It's more elegant.
수수한 걸로요
It was clearly a pink one in the photo,
사진 속에는 분홍색이었는데요
bright pink.
핫핑크요
It suits you perfectly.
정말 잘 어울리네요
Let me think—
여기
we're still missing a women's qipao.
여자 치파오가 빠진 것 같은데요
Well,
아니
do we really have to recreate it exactly?
그렇게까지 똑같이 할 필요는 없잖아요
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
please,
제발
let me off this time.
나 좀 봐줘요
Alright then.
알았어요
But since we're here,
근데 이왕 왔으니까
I'll wear a flower crown myself.
내가 입을게요
I think
보니까
it's you who wanted to wear one
처음부터
from the very beginning.
당신이 하고 싶었던 거죠?
That's right.
맞아요
The moment I saw your photo,
당신 사진을 본 그 순간부터
my heart was already set on it.
하고 싶었어요
Ma'am, could you pick a color for me?
아주머니, 색깔 하나 골라 주세요
Alright.
골라 줄게요
After you're done, you can go take pictures by the seaside.
다 하고 바닷가에 가서 사진 찍으면
It'll look so pretty.
정말 예뻐요
The seaside?
바닷가요?
The seaside.
바닷가요
Yeah.
네
The beach around here is quite beautiful.
여기 바다가 꽤 예뻐서
Photos look even better there.
바다에서 찍으면 더 예쁠 거예요
Look.
저기 봐요
There's a message in a bottle over there.
유리병 편지예요
What a coincidence.
신기하네요
It really is... quite a coincidence.
진짜 신기하네요
Why don't you open it?
열어 볼래요?
Don't tell me
설마
there's an engagement ring hidden inside.
안에 프러포즈 반지라도 숨겨 놨어요?
No ring.
반지는 없어요
It's an application form.
지원서예요
[Yongchuan University PhD Program Application Form]
[융촨 대학교 박사 지원서]
♪ Two souls aligned ♪
♪ 두 영혼이 서로 기대어 ♪
When I accompanied you back to Yongchuan University last time,
지난번에 당신이랑 융촨 대학교 갔을 때
Director Jia asked
자 주임님께서
♪ In silent gravity ♪
♪ 말 없는 끌림 속에 머무네 ♪
if you wanted to go back and finish your PhD.
박사 과정 계속할 생각이 있냐고 물어보셨잖아요
♪ Heal my heart ♪
♪ 너의 모든 것으로 ♪
From the look in your eyes at that time,
당신 눈빛을 보니까
♪ With every part of you ♪
♪ 내 모든 외로움을 치유해 ♪
I could tell you did.
아무래도...
♪ Our words flow ♪
♪ 말들은 잔잔히 흘러 ♪
I'm sure I wasn't wrong.
내가 잘못 본 게 아니죠?
♪ A gentle stream ♪
♪ 부드러운 시냇물처럼 ♪
So this whole elaborate plan...
이것 때문에
was all for this?
이렇게 공을 들였어요?
♪ They glow like fireflies ♪
♪ 반딧불처럼 희미한 빛이 ♪
After we finish the last match,
마지막 경기만 끝나면
♪ Inside a silken dream ♪
♪ 포근한 꿈으로 스며들어 ♪
the kids will have to prepare for the college entrance exam.
애들은 대입 시험을 준비해야 하잖아요
I think after that,
그때가 되면
♪ We talk the cool night, breeze away ♪
♪ 밤새 이야기를 나누면 저녁 바람도 사라지고 ♪
you should start a new chapter too.
당신도 새출발을 해야죠
When did you prepare this?
언제 준비했어요?
♪ We trace the roads ♪
♪ 끝없이 이어지는 ♪
Early this morning.
아침 일찍부터
I forced Yu Bo to come and do it.
위보를 닦달해서 왔어요
♪ That never see an end ♪
♪ 먼 길을 같이 걸어가 ♪
I couldn't let him put me through all that last night for nothing.
밤새 날 괴롭혔는데 그냥 둘 순 없잖아요
♪ We softly calm the hidden doubt ♪
♪ 서로의 눈 속 망설임을 ♪
More than being my wife,
왕파의 아내가 되는 것보다
I want you...
난 당신이
♪ Seen in each other's eyes ♪
♪ 살며시 어루만지네 ♪
to be the radiant, shining Lin Wanxing you are.
반짝반짝 빛나는 린완싱이 됐으면 좋겠어요
♪ And wake the warmth inside ♪
♪ 마음 깊은 곳에 숨겨 둔 온기를 다시 깨워 ♪
♪ Life begins alone ♪
♪ 인생은 원래 홀로 떠나는 거야 ♪
♪ A road we walk alone ♪
♪ 혼자 걷는 궤적이지 ♪
♪ Until fate brings warmth ♪
♪ 운명이 따뜻함을 보내 주는 순간까지 ♪
♪ To light our way back home ♪
♪ 귀로의 방향을 비춰줘 ♪
♪ True love is not just ♪
♪ 진정한 사랑은 ♪
♪ The gaze when two hearts first meet ♪
♪ 첫 만남 그 순간의 눈맞춤이 아니라 ♪
♪ It's courage in the arms ♪
♪ 서로를 껴안을 때의 단단한 용기야 ♪
Are you still going to take photos of me?
내 사진 찍어 줄래요?
I'll do it right now.
바로 찍어 줄게요
♪ We stand as one ♪
♪ 우린 함께 의지해 ♪
♪ Our words flow ♪
♪ 말들은 잔잔히 흘러 ♪
[Yongchuan University PhD Program Application Form]
[융촨 대학교 박사 지원서]
♪ A gentle stream ♪
♪ 부드러운 시냇물처럼 ♪
♪ They glow like fireflies ♪
♪ 반딧불처럼 희미한 빛이 ♪
♪ Inside a silken dream ♪
♪ 포근한 꿈으로 스며들어 ♪
♪ We talk the cool night, breeze away ♪
♪ 밤새 이야기를 나누면 저녁 바람도 사라지고 ♪
What should we eat later?
좀 이따 뭐 먹을까?
Boss,
대장
Wen Chengye.
원청예
-Wen! -Wen Chengye!
- 청예 - 원청예
Wen Chengye,
원청예
don't forget the team meeting this afternoon.
오후에 팀 회의 있는 거 잊지 마
-Got it. -It's about us reaching the finals!
- 알았어 - 우리 결승전에 들어갔다고
Did you hear that?
들었지?
We made it to the finals!
결승 진출이야
Got it!
알았어
Qin Ao is so handsome.
친아오 진짜 잘생겼다
They made it to the finals.
결승전에 진출했대
Qin Ao is so cool!
친아오, 진짜 잘생겼다
Qin Ao, you're so cool!
멋져, 친아오
Let's go watch it together!
우리 같이 보러 가자
So cool!
진짜 잘생겼어
Go for it!
힘내
Look what this is.
다들 이것 좀 봐
Everyone!
학생 여러분
Hello, Director.
주임 선생님, 안녕하세요
-Take a look at these. -Hello, Director.
- 이게 뭘까? - 안녕하세요
I heard from Ms. Lin
린 선생님이
that you guys like this place's milk tea the best.
너희가 이 집 밀크티를 제일 좋아한다길래
Today, I, Qian,
오늘 내가
paid out of my own pocket
내 사비로
to reward all our warriors!
우리 장군들을 위로하러 왔다
Good job, everyone!
다들 고생했어
Thank you, Director!
감사합니다, 선생님
-Let me have one. -Which one?
- 먹자 - 고르자
Director,
선생님
you're being awfully generous today.
오늘 한턱 크게 내셨네요
Was I really that stingy before?
내가 전에는 그렇게 짠돌이였나?
Of course.
짠돌이였죠
Isn't this the first time you've ever bought us anything?
처음 사 주시는 거잖아요
Alright.
그래
I'll buy more next time!
다음엔 더 많이 사 줄게
Students...
여러분
Director Qian,
선생님
you might as well just call us "little brats" like before.
그냥 예전처럼 이 자식들이라고 불러 주세요
It's more affectionate.
그게 더 정겨워요
Alright,
그래
little brats!
이 자식들
I'm really happy today.
오늘 정말 기쁘구나
Seeing how far you've all come
너희가 오늘 같은 날을 맞이하다니
makes every bit of it worthwhile—
내가
all those hours I spent
돋보기를 쓰고
wearing my reading glasses, helping you fill your composition grids
한 칸 한 칸 원고지를 채워 주고
one square at a time, and copying English poems line by line.
한 줄 한 줄 영시를 베껴 준 보람이 있구나
It was all worth it.
보람이 있어
Alright.
그래
I'm here today
오늘 내가 이 자리에 온 건
representing the school
학교를 대표해서
to talk to you all about
너희에게 특별 전형에 대해
the special admission policy.
설명해 주기 위해서다
I think they had it last year.
작년에도 있었던 것 같아
Special admission.
특별 전형
What exactly is it?
특별 전형이 무엇이냐?
Well, the football game
곧
is about to start,
축구 시합이 시작되지
and it's the finals.
그것도 결승전이다
If you win
만약 이번 결승전에서
the championship,
너희가 우승을 차지한다면
3 players among you
너희 중 세 명의 선수는
may qualify for special university admission.
특별 전형으로 대학에 입학할 자격을 얻을 수 있다
That's what special admission means.
이것이 바로 특별 전형이다
Director,
선생님
how many points can it lower the admission threshold by?
특별 전형이면 커트라인이 얼마나 낮아요?
I looked into it.
내가 알아봤는데
Based on your current grades,
너희 지금 성적이면
if you guys push a little harder,
조금만 더 노력하면
you should be able to reach
충분히 특별 전형 커트라인에
[Special Admission]
[특별 전형]
the score requirement for special admission.
가능할 것 같더라
Does it only apply if we win the championship?
꼭 우승해야만 하나요?
Well, of course, the runner-up works too.
물론 준우승도 가능한데
It's just that there won't be
이렇게
those 3
세 명이라는
fixed special admission slots.
고정 TO가 없을 뿐이야
So obviously, winning the championship is better.
그러니 우승하는 게 좋겠지
Really,
정말
the school hopes you can achieve good results.
학교에서는 너희가 좋은 성적을 거두길 바란다
[Special Admission]
[특별 전형]
But...
그리고
I'd
내가 너희한테
also like to say
해 주고 싶은 말이 좀 있다
a few words from the heart.
좀 길어질 수도 있어
I still remember two years ago,
2년 전이 생각나는구나
when you first came to this school.
너희가 이 학교에 들어오는 걸 내가 지켜봤지
You were even rowdier back then.
그때는 지금보다 더 시끄러웠다
But
하지만
your eyes were shining with light.
두 눈은 반짝반짝 빛났어
I thought to myself then
그때 난
that you were a bunch of good boys with ambition.
너희는 포부가 있는 멋진 녀석들이라고 생각했다
But not long after,
그런데 얼마 안 가서
your class fell apart,
반은 흩어지고
and so did your spirits.
상처도 받았지
Especially
특히
that light in your eyes—
눈에 있던 빛이
I could no longer see it.
사라졌더라고
It worried me deeply.
난 마음이 조급해져서
I really wanted to do something for you,
정말 너희를 위해 뭐라도 해 주고 싶었다
but
그런데
there was only so much I could do.
마음은 앞서지만 힘이 부족하더구나
Later,
그러다
Mr. Lin found me
린 어르신이 날 찾아오셔서
and asked me to be this "mystery person"
미스터리 맨이 돼서
to carry out this secret plan.
비밀 계획을 실행해 달라고 하시더군
I was very happy.
정말 기뻤다
I agreed on the spot
망설이지도 않고
without a moment's hesitation.
그 자리에서 바로 승낙했어
I have always believed
난 항상
that as an educator,
교육자로서
we must never let
절대 학생들 마음속의
the fire in the students' hearts go out.
불꽃이 꺼지게 둬선 안 된다고 생각했다
And now, I'm truly happy
지금 난 정말 기쁘다
to see
너희들 마음속 불꽃이 다시 타오르는 걸 봐서 말이야
Really.
정말
No matter whether you win
이번에 너희가 우승을
the championship this time or not,
차지하든 못하든
in my heart,
내 마음속에
you are all the best.
너희는 최고야
I can proudly say
난 자랑스럽게 말할 수 있다
that I
나는
am a teacher of Hongjing No. 8 High School's star football team.
훙징 제8고 스타 축구팀의 선생님이라고
Our football players
우리 축구팀 선수들은
are the best.
최고다
The absolute best.
정말 훌륭해
Qian,
첸 선생님
the other day, Chen Jianghe and I snuck off with your bike
그날 제가 천장허랑 선생님 자전거를 몰래 타다가
and ended up breaking it.
고장을 냈어요
Now it makes a rattling noise whenever you ride it.
자전거가 삐걱거릴 텐데
Don't worry.
걱정하지 마세요
I'll definitely fix it for you.
제가 꼭 고쳐 드릴게요
Good.
그래
Since you're being real with me,
정말 의리가 있구나
I've got to be real with you too.
나도 의리를 보여 줘야지
I wasn't going to tell you at first,
원래는 말을 안 하려고 했는데
but now
너희에게
I'll share another piece of good news with you.
좋은 소식 하나를 더 알려 주마
In order to
학교에서
let you focus wholeheartedly on preparing for the finals,
너희가 이번 결승전을 마음 편히 준비할 수 있도록
starting next week,
다음 주부터
the school is giving you 2 weeks off
2주간 방학을 주고
for intensive training!
합숙 훈련을 하기로 했다
Two weeks?
2주?
Thank you, Director!
주임님, 감사합니다
Alright, alright!
됐어, 그만해
M-M-My job here is done.
내 임무는 다 끝났으니까
You guys, enjoy the milk tea.
밀크티나 마셔
-Enjoy the milk tea. -Okay, okay.
- 얼른 - 네
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
- 난 간다 - 안녕히 가세요
See you tomorrow!
내일 봬요
That's great!
잘됐다
Fight on, guys!
힘내자, 얘들아!
-Fight on! -Yeah!
- 파이팅
Just got the news—
방금 들었는데
Hengjiu defeated their opponent 7-0 with ease
헝주가 7 대 0으로 가볍게
and advanced to the Youth Super League finals.
유소년 슈퍼 리그 결승에 진출했대
We fought tooth and nail to advance,
우린 얻어터지면서 겨우 올라왔는데
while they cruised through.
걔들은 손쉽게 올라왔네
That final boss really is a final boss,
역시 끝판왕은 끝판왕이야
scoring like that in the semifinals.
준결승에서 저런 점수를 내다니
They're just
실력이 우리랑
in a league of their own.
차원이 다르잖아
When we face them in the finals,
결승전에서 만나면
it'll be like two bitter rivals
그야말로 원수를
going head-to-head.
외나무다리에서 만나는 거지
Starting tomorrow,
내일부터
[Little Savage Tribe]
[야인 부족]
we'll focus on analyzing Hengjiu's playing style and discuss
헝주의 스타일을 집중적으로 분석하고
-targeted tactics for the finals. -Coach has new strategies.
- 결승전 전술을 논의할 거다 - 코치님이 전술을 세우셨나 봐
But
하지만
no matter how good the tactics are,
아무리 전술이 대단해도
can we really beat the final boss?
끝판왕을 이길 수 있을까?
After all, in our last match against them,
지난번 경기에서
they scored 11 goals against us.
우리는 11골이나 먹혔잖아
You can still eat?
밥이 넘어가냐?
Why wouldn't I?
왜 안 넘어가?
Is being this dejected
그렇게 풀 죽어 있으면
going to help you win the match?
경기 때 이길 수 있겠어?
Well said.
맞는 말이야
Eat as much as we can now,
지금 실컷 먹고
and give it everything we've got on the field later.
경기 때 실컷 뛰자
Not eating?
안 먹어?
I'm eating then.
내가 먹는다
Come on, eat up.
먹자
I think we should stop being intimidated.
다들 너무 겁먹지 마
Who cares if they're the final boss?
끝판왕이면 어때?
At least we have a chance to compete against them.
같이 경쟁할 기회는 있잖아
Cheer up, guys.
다들 기운 내
Just do our best.
힘내자고
-Come on, guys. -Yeah.
- 힘내자 - 그래
Cheer up, guys.
기운 내자고
That's right.
맞아
And we've got a world-class coach.
우리에겐 월드클래스 감독님도 계시잖아
We have to master the 4-4-2 Formation.
우리는 4-4-2 포메이션을 꼭 마스터해야 해
That way, we won't panic and let Yongchuan Hengjiu
그래야 융촨 헝주를 상대할 때
throw us off our game.
우리 페이스를 잃지 않을 거야
So where are we going to train?
그럼 우리 어디서 훈련해?
Where else?
어디긴 어디야?
The school field.
학교 운동장이지
We only have two weeks left.
우리한테 남은 시간은 2주뿐인데
And they have PE classes there every day.
매일 체육 수업이 있어서
Realistically, we only have
실제로 우리가 쓸 수 있는 시간은
about half a day to train.
반나절 정도밖에 안 돼
Besides, the school closes every day,
그리고 학교는 매일 문을 닫으니까
so we won't even be able to use the field.
훈련장을 쓸 수가 없잖아
And now with new tactics too,
새로운 전술을 익혀야 하는데
there's simply no time to get everything in sync.
손발 맞출 시간이 전혀 없어
That makes sense.
그렇긴 하네
Then, where does Yongchuan Hengjiu
그럼 융촨 헝주는
usually train?
평소에 어디서 훈련해?
This is their training field.
여기가 헝주 훈련장이야
-Oh my god. -What the hell?
- 대박 - 뭐야?
I've never trained at a place
저렇게 좋은 시설에서는
this high-end before.
훈련해 본 적도 없는데
So what if their field's so fancy?
경기장이 좋으면 뭐 해?
Doesn't mean a thing if you can't win,
못 이기면 소용없지
right?
안 그래?
Don't chicken out.
겁먹지 말고
Just go for it.
그냥 붙자
Yeah.
맞아
When have I ever been afraid of anyone?
무서울 거 없잖아
-You can't defeat me. -Let me take another look.
- 이길 수 있어 - 한 번 더 보자
Let me see.
보고 싶어
Get your spirits up, will you?
사기 좀 올리자
Wait.
아니...
Are you serious?
진짜 이런 데서 해?
As for aerobic endurance,
유산소 지구력은
I think our midfielders are the ones who need to focus on it.
미드필더가 훈련하는 게 좋을 것 같아
Zheng Ren, what do you think?
정런, 네 생각은 어때?
Actually, I think aerobic endurance
유산소 지구력은
helps with
좋은 훈련이야
those short bursts
왜냐하면 우리는
of explosive movement, you know?
단기간에 폭발시켜야 하잖아
And Fu, I think you should train more on that too.
신수도 더 훈련하면 좋을 것 같아요
Yeah, we need to work on it together.
응, 같이 하자
No.
아니...
My former manager,
전 매니저
do me a favor.
나 좀 도와줘
Zheng Ren!
정런
Pass the ball!
패스
Over here!
여기로
Chen Jianghe!
천장허
It's okay, it's okay.
괜찮아
Keep moving forward, forward.
앞으로 가
Zheng Ren!
정런
You've watched this match footage over a dozen times already.
이 경기를 벌써 열 번이나 넘게 봤어요
Yeah.
맞아요
The more I watch it, the more anxious I get.
보면 볼수록 불안해지네요
What should we do?
어떡하죠?
We don't even have a proper training facility
우린 전문 훈련장도 없어서
for specialized drills.
맞춤 훈련도 못 하는데
Are we definitely going to lose?
지는 거 아닐까요?
Don't worry.
걱정하지 말아요
I'm their coach.
내가 코치잖아요
This is my job.
이건 내 일이에요
I'm confiscating
불안의 근원은
your source of anxiety.
압수할게요
All set.
해결했어
Come on.
가요
Let's go out for a drink.
나가서 한잔할까요?
A drink?
한잔하자고요?
If you want to drink, why don't we just make something at your place?
술 마실 거면 당신 집에서 마시면 되잖아요
The atmosphere is different.
분위기가 다르잖아요
Going out for a walk
밖에 나가서 좀 걸으면
will help you feel less anxious.
불안도 사라질 거예요
I don't want to move.
움직이기 싫어요
I'm not in the mood.
그럴 기분이 아니에요
If you come with me,
나랑 같이 가면
I'll give you a big gift
내가 당신한테
that you'll definitely love.
당신이 좋아할 만한 큰 선물을 줄게요
Bigger than that PhD application form?
박사 과정 지원서보다 더 큰 선물이요?
It holds a different meaning.
의미가 다르죠
Fine.
알았어요
The stars by the sea are so bright.
바닷가의 별은 진짜 밝네요
If you like,
당신이 좋으면
we can come here often.
자주 와요
We can also see stars like these
이런 별은
from the rooftop where we have tutoring classes.
공부방 옥상에서도 볼 수 있어요
I think a certain someone
내가 보기에 누구는
is just lazy.
그냥 게으른 거 같네요
After building up the suspense for so long,
이렇게 오래 밑밥을 깔았으니
you can
내 선물을
bring out the gift for me.
꺼내도 돼요
"All set."
'해결했어'
I heard your call
당신이 위보랑 통화할 때
with Yu Bo.
들었거든요
When he said "all set,"
해결했다는 게
did you mean you've secured a training ground?
훈련장 문제 아니에요?
I'm wrong?
틀렸어요?
Then you can call Chairman Wang Genfa
그럼 왕건파 회장님한테
now.
전화해도 되고요
Chairman Wang Genfa is very stingy.
왕건파 회장님은 짠돌이예요
Then I'll make the call.
그럼 내가 걸게요
You guessed right.
맞혔어요
I've booked the best training facility in Hongjing
훙징에서 제일 좋은 훈련장이랑
and a hotel where the team can stay together.
합숙 관리 호텔까지 예약했어요
And I didn't book Hengjiu's place.
그리고 헝주 돈이 아니라
I paid for it myself.
내 돈으로 했어요
No more words.
내 마음은
Let's drink to it.
이 술에 다 담았어요
Cheers.
건배
Are you cold?
추워요?
A bit.
조금요
Come on.
이리 와요
A crab!
게다
Where did it go?
어디 갔지?
Where did you get it?
어디서 났어요?
They say when fireworks burn,
불꽃이 터질 때
they create a "wish frequency."
소원을 이뤄 주는 주파수가 나오는데
If your heartbeat syncs with it at that moment,
그때 당신 심장 박동이 주파수와 같아지면
your wish will definitely come true.
소원이 이뤄진대요
Looks like you've been reading
우리 왕 코치님이
quite a few psychology books, Coach Wang.
심리학 책을 꽤 읽었나 보네요
Give it a try?
해 봐요
Let's make a wish together
우승하게 해 달라고
to win the championship.
같이 소원 빌어요
You know what?
그거 알아요?
These sparks are made of magnesium.
불꽃은 마그네슘으로 이루어져 있는데
Magnesium reacts with carbon dioxide.
마그네슘과 이산화탄소가 만나 화학 반응을 일으키는 거라
So you can't put them out with a fire extinguisher.
소화기로는 못 꺼요
You've switched to being a chemistry teacher, huh?
요즘 화학 선생님으로 전향했나 봐요?
Wait.
잠깐만요
To put out the fire...
불을 끄려면
you just need to cover a large area
넓은 면적으로 덮어서
♪ I caught your eyes ♪
♪ 난 네 눈빛을 포착했어 ♪
to cut off the carbon dioxide.
이산화탄소를 차단해야 해요
♪ On the summer night ♪
♪ 그 여름밤에 ♪
♪ Like stars that glow so bright ♪
♪ 눈부시게 반짝이던 별처럼 ♪
♪ A spark in my heart ♪
♪ 마음속 한 떨기의 불꽃이 ♪
♪ Lost in a dream secretly ♪
♪ 꿈속에서 조용히 사라져 갔어 ♪
♪ With the evening breeze whispering in my ear ♪
♪ 저녁 바람이 귓가에 고백을 전하면 ♪
♪ Fireworks bloom across the sky ♪
♪ 하늘 가득 불꽃이 피어나고 ♪
♪ Shimmering in your eyes ♪
♪ 그 빛이... ♪
-The kids are urging us... -Let's go.
- 애들이 재촉하네요 - 가요
Let's go find them.
애들한테 가야죠
Good evening.
얘들아, 안녕
-Ms. Lin.
- 린 선생님
Ms. Lin, Coach!
- 코치님
Play football...
공을 차서...
-What's wrong? -I can walk by myself.
- 뭐야? - 나 혼자 갈 수 있어요
-Okay, okay. -Let me show you.
- 알았어요 - 내가 보여 줄게
Ms. Lin is here. Ms. Lin is here.
선생님 오셨어
-Ms. Lin. -Coach.
- 린 선생님 - 코치님
-You called us here this late... -Attention.
- 한밤중에 불러서... - 차렷
Big drinker, tiny tolerance.
실력은 꽝인데
She's drunk.
열정만 넘치지
Please sit down, everyone.
다들 앉아
Listen to your supervisor.
선생님 말씀 들어야지
Sit... Where should I sit?
앉자
Do you still remember
다들 기억해?
how you felt when you signed this football?
이 공에 사인할 때 기분이 어땠는지
Signed football.
사인 축구공이네요
When we make it big,
나중에 우리가 성공하면
this'll be priceless.
그 축구공은 엄청난 보물이 될 거야
Now it really feels like a football team with star players.
꼭 축구 스타가 된 것 같아
Yes.
좋아
Technique.
내 사인 죽이지?
My turn, my turn.
나도 할래
Don't be so quick to forget.
상처 아물었다고 또 까먹지 마
It's for Fu's sake.
푸신수 부탁이니까
I'll just scribble something.
난 대충 사인할게
Cool.
멋있다
Quit pretending, dude.
그만 좀 허세 부려
Here, pen.
펜 받아
So annoying.
진짜 귀찮게 하네
Alright, boys.
자, 얘들아
It's about time.
시간 다 됐다
Hurry up and go to training.
얼른 훈련하러 가자
[Feng Suo]
[펑쒀]
Whoever wasn't serious back then
그때 누가 대충 했는지
knows it in their own heart.
자기들이 잘 알 거야
Actually,
사실은
there's something very important
아직 마무리를 못 한
I still haven't done.
중요한 일이 있었어
[Feng Suo]
[펑쒀]
[Lin]
[린]
[Lin Wanxing]
[린완싱]
Are you willing to sign it now, Mr. Coach?
이제 사인해 주실 거죠 왕 코치님?
♪ A starlit night ♪
♪ 밤하늘의 별빛 ♪
♪ Secrets falling into my palm ♪
♪ 손바닥 위로 떨어진 은밀한 속삭임, 속삭임 ♪
♪ Unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ 수수께끼를 풀고 ♪
♪ It was you who gave me this brilliance ♪
♪ 내게 눈부신 빛을 선물한 건 너야, 바로 너 ♪
[Lin Wanxing]
[린완싱]
♪ Lasting memories ♪
♪ 기나긴 기억 ♪
♪ The distance that brings our dreams closer ♪
♪ 꿈과 가까워진 거리 그 거리 ♪
♪ To run toward you ♪
♪ 너에게 달려가기 위해 ♪
♪ I keep practicing with no turning back ♪
♪ 난 거침없이 연습 또 연습해 ♪
[Wang Fa]
[왕파]
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 두려울 게 없어 ♪
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪
♪ The light shimmers ♪
♪ 희미한 빛이 비쳐 ♪
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 별처럼 찬란하게 빛나 ♪
♪ Running towards you ♪
♪ 널 향해 달려가 ♪
♪ I keep moving fearlessly ♪
♪ 두려움 없이 앞으로 나아가 ♪
♪ Walk side by side ♪
♪ 나란히 함께 ♪
♪ Become ourselves ♪
♪ 나 자신이 되어 ♪
♪ Amid the storm ♪
♪ 폭풍 속에서 ♪
♪ As our breaths slowly intertwine ♪
♪ 천천히 다가오는 숨결, 숨결 ♪
♪ Heartbeats alternating ♪
♪ 교차하는 심장 소리 ♪